# RAHUL SHIAL



CALGARY, AB

rahul.shial@gmail.com



+1(587) 889-2503



in rahulshial



<u> rahulshial</u>

Having spent my career as a programmer/analyst for 15 years, and as a Project Manager for another 15 years, I have gained extensive experience in the software development / IT world. After learning new technologies, and cutting my teeth at Curbie, I have a proven history of strong ethics and a passion for web development. Excited and eager to pursue new companies to grow my skills with the ability to adapt in both self-starting and collaborative environments while staying focused on achieving high-quality results under strict deadlines.

#### Skills

Database Postgres, Firebase

Languages Javascript/TypeScript, CSS, jQuery, HTML, COBOL

Frameworks / Libraries NodeJS, NestJS, NextJs, ReactJS, TypeORM, Axios, AJAX, Express, Material-UI, CSS Tailwind,

JEST, Heroku, AWS, BitBucket, GitHub, Twilio, JIRA, Notion, FIGMA

#### **Work Experience**

**Lighthouse Labs** Apr2021 - Present

Project Evaluator and Mentor focussing on students in weeks 1 – 4 of the bootcamp. Guiding and coaching students to research solutions, mentoring them on programming aspects utilizing JavaScript and Single Page web Apps using React.

Clutch Canada Jan 2022 - Jun 2022

As a Software Developer, enhanced and maintained the JS-React based customer and operations application related to purchase of vehicles (Sell-To-Clutch) using Javascript, React, NodeJS, Sequelize, Postgres and related frameworks.

- Selected Projects:
  - Sell-To-Clutch:
    - Upgraded workflow (FE & BE) to enable customer input exact data which goes thru an algorithm to determine and give an instant offer to the customer for their vehicle.
    - Upon getting the instant offer, the customer can schedule a pick-up / drop-off of his vehicle. The customer also had the functionality to convert his sell into a trade-in and purchase another vehicle from Clutch.
    - These enhancements increased conversion by over 60% in one month and 15% YOY. Vehicle appraisals increased 5x to over 1500/month.
  - Offer Overview Page:
    - Redesigned the Offer Overview page for operations to display the vehicle being purchased, along with associated purchase orders (for trade-ins).
    - Allow the operations to upload, review, approve/reject documents related to the vehicle being purchased.

**Curbie Cars** May 2021 - Jan 2022

As a Software Developer, enhanced and maintained a dynamic and scalable web-application using TypeScript/JS, React, Redux, Material-ui/CSS Tailwind, NestJS, TypeORM and Postgres. Upgraded the existing back-end servers with better error handling / logging, with integration to Slack messaging. Contributed towards migrating images and documents from Cloudinary to AWS S3.

- Selected Projects:
  - 2 new vehicle status fields:
    - Add 2 new status fields to the vehicle database (Postgres, Javascript, TypeORM), and create a onetime migration algorithm to convert the existing status to Operations Status and / or Listing Status
    - Update the api-server (Ruby on Rails) to allow CRUD operations along with validations for these 2 new status fields (remove CRUD and validations from old status field)
    - Update the client-api-server (Javascript, TypeORM) to update the Operations Status and Listing Status when a customer checks out a vehicle for purchase
    - Update the operations-client (Javascript, React, Redux) to update the Operations Status & Listing Status when a vehicle is procured and moves thru the operations from procurement thru ready to sell.
    - Update the customer-client (Javascript/TypeScript, React, Redux) to use the Operations & Listing statuses to display a vehicle for purchase and update the same when a customer checks out the vehicle for purchase.

## RAHUL SHIAL, PMP®

- Redesign Vehicle Page for operations:
  - Create a brand-new Vehicle Edit landing page for operations with multiple tabs that included the Dashboard, GeneralInfo, Features, History&Warranty, Pricing, Reconditioning & Specifications. Of these Dashboard & Specifications were view only, the others being updatable.
  - History & Warranty had a feature to upload Carfax Report.

DXC Technology Dec 2019 – Jan 2020

- As a Sr. Project Manager, I managed multiple projects for Small & Medium Business customers, implementing
  customized Microsoft Dynamics solutions, upgrading their current platforms, including data migrations, 3rd party
  vendor coordination.
- Actively develop customer relationships to execute upgrade and customization projects in the Microsoft NAV & D365 environments.

#### Zedi Solutions Inc, - Calgary, AB

Jun 2014 to Oct 2018

- As a Sr. Project Manager, I managed E2E complex migration projects in North America for Oil & gas producers while retaining gross margins of more than 40%.
- Worked extensively with the customer as a Business Analyst to capture detailed requirements, baseline the scope and deliver complex solutions to the customer satisfaction.
- Developed & implemented automated monitoring & tracking of Projects which helped in accurately reporting to the PMO and SLT.

### **Early Career**

<ul> <li>Project Management Specialist, Innoworth Tech Pvt Ltd</li> </ul>	Aug 2013 to May 2014
Sr. Project Manager, TechMahindra Ltd	Oct 2009 to Jul 2013
Lead Consultant, Capgemini	Sep 2004 to Sep 2008
Technical Lead, PSI Data Systems Pvt. Ltd	Oct 2002 to Aug 2004
Technical Lead, PSI Data Systems Pvt. Ltd	Oct 2002 to Aug 2004
<ul> <li>Lead Analyst / Programmer III, Ajilon Consulting LLC</li> </ul>	May 1997 to Jun 2002
• Sr. Systems Executive, Patni Computer Systems Ltd.	Jun 1996 to Apr 1997
Sr. Analyst / Programmer, Infrasoft Technologies	Sep 1995 to May 1996
EDP Supervisor, Abu Dhabi Commercial Bank Ltd.	Jun 1993 to Aug 1995
Sr. Systems Executive, Sir Ratan Tata Computer Center	Mar 1991 to May 1993
Systems Executive, Monarch Computer Center	Aug 1990 to Feb 1991

#### **Education**

- Bachelor of Commerce (Financial Accounting & Auditing) University of Mumbai 1990.
- Diploma in Web Development 2021.